{"tossups": [{"question": "The title of a short story by this author comes from a phrase appearing on the edges of maps in the \u201cviking age.\u201d In that story, people venture to a paradise-like planet but report it empty. Another story by this author describes the burned shadows of people who died in a nuclear explosion; that story is \u201cThere Will Come Soft Rains.\u201d That story appears in this author\u2019s anthology (*) The Martian Chronicles. Another novel by this author includes a protagonist who memorizes parts of Ecclesiastes after his copy of the Bible was burned. For ten points, name this author of Something Wicked this Way Comes, Dandelion Wine, and Fahrenheit 451.", "answer": "Ray Bradbury", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This man won a prize from the Academy of Metz for an essay criticizing royal absolutism. C\u00e9cile Renault planned to kill this man, so this man had Renault and her family executed. Originally a lawyer from Arras, this man opposed Jean-Jacques Brissot\u2019s warmongering and sponsored the (*) Cult of the Supreme Being. During his period of preeminence, this man oversaw purges of the Girondins, the Herbtists, and Georges Danton, but was eventually toppled and executed amidst the Thermidorian Reaction. For ten points, name this \u201cincorruptible\u201d radical Jacobin and leading figure during the French Revolution\u2019s Reign of Terror.", "answer": "Maximilien Robespierre", "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"question": "An October 2017 editorial by The New York Times called the treatment of these people \u201cone of those wrenching tragedies that beggars understanding.\u201d Members of this ethnic group are targeted by the 969 Movement and are concentrated in the Rakhine state. Since August 2017, \u201cclearance\u201d operations against these people have caused hundreds of thousands of (*) refugees to flee to Bangladesh, while Nobel Laureate Aung San Suu Kyi has been criticized for her silence on the treatment of these people. For ten points, name this predominantly Muslim ethnic group who face persecution at the hands of the government of Burma.", "answer": "The Rohingya people (prompt on \u201cBurmese\u201d, or \u201cBurmese Muslims\u201d)", "category": "Current Events"}, {"question": "Pen Sovan founded this nation\u2019s People\u2019s Revolutionary Party, which abandoned Marxist policies under the leadership of Heng Samrin. An empire based in this country grew out of the Chenla kingdom, and this nation\u2019s dark ages began after being conquered by the Ayutthaya Kingdom. This Asian nation\u2019s monarchy ended after a 1950 coup against King (*) Sihanouk. One infamous leader of this nation declared 1975 to be \u201cYear Zero\u201d and purged thousands of \u201cNew People\u201d in killing fields. For 10 points, name this country, home to Angkor Wat, which endured the regime of Pol Pot and the Khmer Rouge.", "answer": "Cambodia", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Pony Penning occurs annually in Assateague Island in this body of water. The Calvert Cliffs extend for over 20 miles along this estuary, which is crossed by the Lucius Kellam Bridge\u2013Tunnel. Skipjacks are traditionally used in one of this body of water\u2019s largest industries, and it receives the James and (*) Susquehanna Rivers. The Potomac River also empties into this body of water, in which pollution over the past 75 years has critically damaged populations of oysters and blue crabs. For ten points, name this large bay which borders Virginia and Maryland.", "answer": "the Chesapeake Bay", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "One character in this work is punished with \u201cThe Tickler.\u201d The person who cared for that character is eventually severely brain damaged. A house in this work has all of the clocks stopped at the time its owner was left at the altar; that is Satis House. The protagonist of this work is scared into (*) stealing food and a metal file for a convict he meets. That convict ends up being the benefactor of the protagonist of this novel, who eventually goes abroad to be a merchant. For ten points, name this novel by Charles Dickens about an English orphan who lives with Mrs. Havisham and becomes a gentleman, Pip.", "answer": "Great Expectations", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This particle\u2019s namesake \u201cannihilation spectroscopy\u201d is used to study defects in solids. The emission of this particle is used in potassium-argon dating. This particle was discovered from observations of its curved track on a lead plate by (*) Carl Anderson. Fluorodeoxyglucose is a source of this particle used to generate gamma rays in their namesake \u201cemission tomography\u201d. These particles were predicted from negative energy solutions to the Dirac equation. A Dalitz pair is composed of one of these particles and an electron. For 10 points, name this positively charged fermion symbolized e+.", "answer": "positron", "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The product of this quantity, reaction cross-section, and the square root of 8kT over pi times mu gives the collision frequency. This quantity is a proportionality constant in the Stark\u2013Einstein law. This value can be obtained through X-ray crystallography of (*) silicon lattices. The number is the quotient of Faraday\u2019s constant and elementary charge. Boltzmann\u2019s constant is defined as the ideal gas constant divided by this value, which is similar to Loschmidt\u2019s constant. For 10 points, name this constant defined as number of units per mole, approximately 6.022*10^23.", "answer": "Avogadro\u2019s number (accept Avogadro\u2019s constant)", "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This figure introduced the practice of Seid, a special type of sorcery, to the Aesir, and in one work this deity is accused of having sex with their sibling. This deity cries tears of red gold for her absentee husband Odr, and Thor (*) impersonated this goddess in order to retrieve his hammer. Half of all fallen soldiers go to Valhalla while the other half are accepted into this goddess\u2019 realm Folkvangr, and this goddess owns the necklace Brisingamen. For 10 points, name this Norse goddess of love, sex, and beauty.", "answer": "Freya (accept Freyja, do not accept or prompt on \u201cFreyr,\u201d \u201cFrey,\u201d or \u201cFrigg\u201d)", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "One variant of this construct named for Zeno differs from this construct in that the time taken for operations decreases exponentially, meaning that the total time converges to some finite value. This is important because it has been shown that it is impossible to know whether or not one of these constructs will (*) terminate. A \u201cuniversal\u201d one of these constructs has the ability to simulate any other one of these constructs, and a \u201cmultitape\u201d one has multiple heads and multiple pieces of tape. For 10 points, name this abstract device, named for an English computer scientist, which can simulate any computer algorithm.", "answer": "Turing machine HALFTIME", "subcategory": "Science Computer Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This work\u2019s subject wears a diamond crescent on her head to evoke the huntress Diana. Exhibited in the Paris Salon of 1884, this painting\u2019s subject originally wore a dress with a strap sliding down before public backlash forced the creator of this work to paint it back on. The namesake figure of this painting boasts extremely pale (*) skin and a haughty, aristocratic expression. The mysteriously named central character of this portrait was really a New Orleans-born socialite named Virginie Gautreau. For ten points, name this work depicting a lady of high society by John Singer Sargent.", "answer": "Portrait of Madame X", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This city contained the Great Cothon and the Tophet of Salammbo. This city fought its former mercenaries in the Truceless War, during which it lost control of Corsica and Sardinia. Cato the Elder urged the destruction of this city, which was finally accomplished in 146 BC by (*) Scipio Aemillianus. In an earlier conflict, forces of this city crossed the Alps and won victories at the Battles of Trebia, Lake Trasimene, and Cannae. That army was led by Hannibal Barca. For ten points, name this city-state on the North African coast which fought the Punic Wars with Rome.", "answer": "Carthage", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This opera contains a choral recitation of the hymn \u201cOh God, look down from heaven.\u201d In this opera, three ladies padlock the mouth of a bird catcher who is later given a set of bells that are used before the \u201cStutter Duet.\u201d In this work, the priest (*) Sarastro requires a prince to complete several trials, and one soprano must hit several high F's in the aria \u201cDer Holle Rache\u201d. This opera centers on a quest to rescue Pamina whose power-seeking mother is the Queen of the Night. For 10 points, name this Wolfgang Mozart singspiel opera that sees Tamino play the title enchanted instrument.", "answer": "The Magic Flute", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Audiovisual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Chiari malformations are structural defects in this structure. Infection can result in damage to this structure in prion diseases and Miller\u2013Fisher syndrome. The primary cells of this structure receive weak signals from the parallel fibers of granule cells and strong signals from climbing fibers. When this structure is attacked by anti-Yo antibodies, (*) Purkinje cells are destroyed. The substantia nigra is located in this structure\u2019s basal ganglia. Damage to this brain structure is tested the same way as drunkenness, due to its function in language, attention, and motor control. For ten points name this part of the brain with a name meaning \u201clittle brain.\u201d", "answer": "cerebellum", "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One of this author\u2019s works is about a group of people, led by Mrs. Aldwinkle, which discusses the glories of the Renaissance. This author of Those Barren Leaves wrote a novel about a house party located at Mr. Wimbush\u2019s title estate, as viewed through the eyes of Denis Stone. Drugs commonly appear in this author\u2019s works, such as in his personal experience detailed in The Doors of Perception and as the ubiquitous (*) soma in another work. That work includes a man named John the Savage who debates the Resident World Controller Mustapha Mond. For ten points name this author of Eyeless in Gaza, Crome Yellow, and Brave New World.", "answer": "Aldous Huxley", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The counting of the Omer lasts from the end of this holiday to the beginning of Shavuot 49 days later. The practice of korban for this holiday is now only continued by Samaritans. One song sung during this holiday repeats the phrase \u201cDayenu\u201d or \u201cit would have sufficed\u201d and the phrase \u201cMa Nishtana\u201d or \u201cWhy is (*) tonight different from other nights?\u201d is asked at the beginning of this holiday. This holiday begins on the fifteenth of Nissan and includes many readings from the Haggadah. Jews celebrate seders and eat unleavened bread during- for ten points- what holiday commemorating the exodus from Egypt.", "answer": "Passover (accept Pesach)", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "Karl Popper advocated for the negative version of the philosophy. Derek Parfit theorized an ethical conundrum in this philosophy known as the \u201cmere addition paradox.\u201d A two-level form of this school created by R. M Hare attempts to unify the rightness of an action through both results and conformity to rules. The founder of the school of philosophy developed a method to (*) quantize the value of pleasure known as felicific calculus. For ten points name this philosophy defined as doing the most good for the greatest number of people which was supported by John Stuart Mill and Jeremy Bentham.", "answer": "utilitarianism", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "This woman founded a charity to combat malnutrition with George Kessler. Writing that \u201cour democracy is but a name,\u201d this woman joined the Industrial Workers of the World and argued against \u201ceducation without revolution.\u201d This woman penned such autobiographical works as Light in my Darkness and Story of My Life, and she cofounded the (*) American Civil Liberties Union in 1920. Earlier in life, this woman attended the Perkins Institute where she learned language and speech from Anne Sullivan. For ten points, name this deaf-and-blind activist from Alabama depicted in The Miracle Worker.", "answer": "Helen Keller", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One work by this composer opens with rapid G triplets that represent a horse\u2019s gallop. Six piano pieces by this man are named Moments Musicaux [Mu-si-coh], and two song cycles written by this man are based on the poetry of Wilhelm Muller. One symphony by this man includes the movements \u201cPhilosopher\u2019s Scherzo\u201d and \u201cMarch of Destiny\u201d and was originally written as (*) incidental music to Rosamunde. This man\u2019s Piano Quintet in A Major was named Die Forelle, and is more commonly known as the Trout Quintet. For 10 points, name this German composer of Der Erlkonig in addition to an \u201cUnfinished\u201d 8th symphony.", "answer": "Franz Schubert", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "The main character of this work takes a daffodil, and places it under her pillow. During an execution, one character bashes the head of an accused in with a rock in order to give him a quicker death. One character tries to flee across the border, but is caught and tortured by The Eyes. That character goes to work as a prostitute at Jezebel\u2019s after escaping the Red Center and is named (*) Moira. The title of this novel refers to the position of the main character, a sort of concubine that exists only to reproduce. For ten points, name this novel set in the republic of Gilead about Offred, written by Margaret Atwood.", "answer": "The Handmaid\u2019s Tale", "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "John Maynard Keynes believed that this man had made a fundamental error in his definition of independence. A relation named for this mathematician states that the probability of at least one event in a collection is no greater than the sum of their individual probabilities, that inequality is also called the (*) union bound. This logician\u2019s namesake \u201csatisfiability problem\u201d is NP-complete. A system introduced by this man has expressions that can be simplified through the use of De Morgan\u2019s identities or Karnaugh Maps. For 10 points, name this English logician who created his namesake algebra using ones and zeros to represent \u201ctrue\u201d and \u201cfalse.\u201d", "answer": "George Boole Bonuses", "subcategory": "Science Math", "category": "Science"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "In this work, a character represented by an oboe is swallowed alive by a character who ends up with a noose around his tail. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Peter and the Wolf", "Sergei Prokofiev", "Scythian Suite"], "parts": ["Name this \u201csymphonic fairy tale\u201d about a boy, represented by the strings, who captures a creature represented by the F horn.", "This Soviet composer wrote Peter and the Wolf.", "This other Prokofiev piece begins with frantic notes meant to represent an invocation of the sun. The last movement of this piece describes the conquest of the Evil God."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "When performed during sewage treatment, this technique uses a bar screen. For ten points each:", "answers": ["filtration (accept equivalents)", "B\u00fcchner funnel", "porosity (accept equivalents, accept void fraction or void ratio)"], "parts": ["Name this process that separates solids from fluids using paper and a funnel.", "This type of funnel, named after a German chemist, is commonly used in filtration. Unlike a Hirsch funnel, the walls of this type of funnel are vertical.", "This property of a filter, which is related to permeability, is the ratio of the volume of the voids in a filter divided by the volume of the whole filter. It is a measure of the empty spaces in a material."], "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about NHL career record holders. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Wayne Gretzky", "Martin Brodeur", "Tiger Williams (accept Dave Williams)"], "parts": ["This Canadian player nicknamed \u201cthe Great One\u201d holds a career record with 869 goals. This forward was controversially traded from Edmonton to Los Angeles after the 1988 Stanley Cup.", "This legendary Devils goalie holds the NHL record for wins. In a 21 year career, this ten-time all-star won three Stanley Cups.", "Perhaps less impressively, the all-time record for NHL penalty minutes belongs to this forward who played for Toronto, Vancouver, and Los Angeles."], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "The Somigliana equation can be used to find the apparent effect of this force. For ten points each:", "answers": ["gravity", "latitude", "modified Newtonian dynamics (accept MOND)"], "parts": ["Name this force that causes an acceleration of about 9.8 meters per second squared on Earth.", "The International Gravity Formula determines Earth\u2019s gravity as a function of this quantity. Differences in this coordinate cause a fluctuation in Earth\u2019s gravity of about 0.05 meters per second squared.", "This theory of gravity uses the function mu to explain the velocity of stars in galaxies. It was created by Mordehai Milgrom in 1983."], "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "You know you\u2019re feared when people start calling you \u201cthe Butcher.\u201d For ten points each:", "answers": ["Valeriano Weyler", "Pompey the Great (prompt on partial answer)", "Che Guevara"], "parts": ["This Spanish leader was dubbed \u201cthe Butcher\u201d by American yellow journalists for his bloody attempts to crush the Cuban independence movement through civilian \u201creconcentration.\u201d", "This general\u2019s father was known as \u201cthe Butcher of Asculum,\u201d leading this man\u2019s opponents to call him \u201cthe Little Butcher.\u201d This Roman leader lost to Julius Caesar at the Battle of Pharsalus and was later killed in Egypt.", "American and Cuban enemies of this Argentine revolutionary dubbed him \u201cthe Butcher of La Caba\u00f1a.\u201d After helping Fidel Castro take control of Cuba, this former doctor was captured and executed in Bolivia."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Amonasro is taken as a prisoner during this opera, however his life is spared by Radames. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Aida", "Giuseppi Verdi", "\u201cThe Triumphal March\u201d (accept \u201cGrand March\u201d)"], "parts": ["Identify this opera in which Radames and Amneris compete for the love of the titular Nubian princess.", "Aida was written by this Italian composer whose other major works include Il Trovatore and Rigoletto.", "After their victory, Radames and his soldiers return to Egypt accompanied by this piece. Many productions of Aida have live elephants accompany the performers during this piece."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Audiovisual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "This relationship is described in the Lotka\u2013Volterra equations. For ten points each:", "answers": ["predator\u2013prey relationship", "aposematism", "M\u00fcllerian mimicry"], "parts": ["Name this relationship between a hunting organism and the organism that is hunted as a food source.", "This antipredator adaptation is seen in poisonous frogs and skunks. This term was coined by Edward Bagnall Poulton to describe warning coloration.", "Aposematism is exploited in this type of mimicry, in which two or more species with strong defenses evolve to resemble each other."], "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This layer of Earth and the upper mantle form the lithosphere. For ten points each:", "answers": ["crust", "asthenosphere", "Gutenberg discontinuity (prompt on \u201ccore\u2013mantle boundary\u201d or \u201cCMB\u201d)"], "parts": ["Name this outermost layer of the Earth. The \u201ccontinental\u201d part of this layer is primarily composed of silicates.", "The lithosphere lies above this other layer of Earth. This region of the upper mantle is ductile and viscous, leading to its name meaning \u201cweak sphere.\u201d", "This structure is the boundary between Earth\u2019s mantle and outer core. It is named for a German-American seismologist."], "subcategory": "Science Other", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This deity rides the elephant Airavata and slew the serpent Vritra. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Indra", "Rigveda", "Asuras (do not accept or prompt on \u201csuras\u201d)"], "parts": ["Name this Vedic god of storms who lives atop Mount Meru and, with Angi, leads the Devas.", "Indra is featured in this ancient collection of Sanskrit hymns. It consists of 10 books called mandalas.", "This other group of Vedic deities competes against the Inra and the Devas for power and was divided into Daityas and Danavas. In earlier texts, the Devas are also considered part of this group."], "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "The poet of this collection began writing them while a guest of Princess Marie von Thurn und Taxis. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Duino Elegies", "Rainer Maria Rilke", "A Young Poet"], "parts": ["Name this collection of poetry that the author was inspired to write after hearing, \u201cWho, if I cried out, would hear me among the angelic orders?\u201d", "This German poet of The Duino Elegies wrote other works like Sonnets to Orpheus and \u201cThe Archaic Torso of Apollo.\u201d", "Rilke wrote a collection of letters to this person, an alter-ego for Franz Xaver Kappus, in which he said that Kappus should feel, love, and seek truth."], "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This work was completed after the Visigothic sack of Rome to reject claims that Christianity was to blame for the Western Roman Empire\u2019s struggles. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The City of God", "St. Augustine of Hippo", "Lucretia (accept Lucrece)"], "parts": ["Name this work of ancient Christian theology which presents history as a running battle between God and the devil.", "This North African philosopher and Bishop of Hippo wrote The City of God.", "In The City of God, Augustine faults this woman for killing herself after being raped because impurity comes from the mind, not the body. This woman\u2019s violation and suicide sparked the overthrow of the Roman monarchy."], "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "The Kingdom of Mutapa controlled land straddling this river from the fifteenth to eighteenth century. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Zambezi River", "Victoria Falls", "Mozambique"], "parts": ["Name this fourth largest river in Africa. It empties into the Indian Ocean and the name of a country formerly called Northern Rhodesia is derived from the name of this river.", "The Zambezi contains this largest waterfall in the world. David Livingstone was likely the first European to explore this waterfall.", "The Zambezi reaches the ocean in this Southeast African country. This former Portuguese colony has its capital at Maputo."], "category": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "Jethro of Midian is considered the chief prophet of this religion. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Druze", "color", "Fatimid Caliphate"], "parts": ["Name this Abrahamic faith and offshoot of Islam which is mainly concentrated in Lebanon and Syria.", "Though opposed to all iconography, Druze adherents depict their beliefs through five of these things. An old flag of Libya included just one of these things to symbolize the power of Islam.", "Many followers of Druze await the return of al-Hakim, a caliph from this Cairo-based dynasty of the high middle ages."], "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "During this period, Harry Truman created the Federal Employees Loyalty Program to ensure civil servants\u2019 proper Americanism. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Second Red Scare", "House Un-American Activities Committee (accept HUAAC)", "Alger Hiss"], "parts": ["Name this period of intense anti-communism during the late 1940s and early 1950s, epitomized by Joseph McCarthy\u2019s investigations.", "During the Second Red Scare, this committee in the House of Representatives scrutinized those suspected of communist leanings, including the blacklisted Hollywood Ten.", "The House Un-American Activities Committee\u2019s most famous prosecution involved this State department official accused of spying for the Soviets. Whittaker Chambers\u2019 testimony led to this man\u2019s conviction for perjury."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "One character in this novel realizes that she is now subservient to a man who had once been her servant. For ten points each:", "answers": ["July\u2019s People", "Nadine Gordimer", "Burger\u2019s Daughter"], "parts": ["Name this novel about a fictional South African civil war in which the Smales family flees Johannesburg with their servant.", "This South African wrote July\u2019s People as a prediction of how Apartheid would end.", "Gordimer also wrote this novel about Rosa, who goes through life fighting against Apartheid despite her efforts being dismissed and almost going into exile."], "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "A white vase with gold trim and a painted rose rests in the right corner of this painting. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Child\u2019s Bath", "Mary Cassatt", "woodblock printing (or equivalents mentioning wood; prompt on \u201cprinting\u201d)"], "parts": ["Name this 1893 oil painting showing a mother helping her young daughter get clean.", "The Child\u2019s Bath was painted by this American Impressionist who depicted many scenes of mothers and their children as well as The Boating Party.", "For The Child\u2019s Bath, Cassatt was inspired by this form of Japanese art. Examples of this style that are predominately blue are called aizuri-e."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "In this epic, the title character angers Ishtar by rejecting her advances, so she sends the bull of heaven to wreak havoc upon his land. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Epic of Gilgamesh", "Enkidu", "a snake"], "parts": ["Name this epic poem about a man who seeks immortality after the death of his best friend.", "This is Gilgamesh\u2019s best friend. He is initially sent down to kill Gilgamesh, but ends up humanizing him after they realize that they are an even match.", "Utnapishtim eventually tells Gilgamesh where to find an herb that will grant him immortality, but this animal eats it while Gilgamesh is asleep."], "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "Much of the action in this novel takes place in the Year of the Depend Adult Undergarment. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Infinite Jest", "tennis", "David Foster Wallace"], "parts": ["Name this novel that centers on a film created by James Incandenza that is so entertaining it kills all its viewers.", "This sport features heavily in Infinite Jest. The Enfield Academy teaches this sport and the game of Eschaton incorporates elements of this sport.", "Infinite Jest was written by this author who committed suicide in 2008. This man also wrote the philosophical essay This is Water."], "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Arthur St. Clair first established American rule over what is now this state. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Michigan", "Toledo", "Lewis Cass"], "parts": ["Name this mid-western state which joined the Union in 1837. Though its capital was initially Detroit, an 1847 constitutional amendment moved it to Lansing.", "Before becoming a state, Michigan lost a bloodless war with Ohio for control of this city. Today the fourth largest in Ohio, this city shares its name with a Spanish town El Greco painted a notable \u201cView of.\u201d", "This statesman was instrumental in exploring and settling Michigan, and later served as the state\u2019s governor and senator. As the 1848 Democratic presidential nominee, this man vocally supported popular sovereignty."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Pope Sixtus IV sanctioned the creation of this institution in 1478. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Spanish Inquisition", "Conversos", "Tom\u00e1s de Torquemada"], "parts": ["Name this tribunal which for centuries investigated heresy in a certain Iberian nation. Apparently, nobody expects it.", "The establishment of the Inquisition was inspired by fears that these people were undermining Christianity by continuing to practice Judaism. This spanish term can be contrasted with moriscos.", "This Dominican friar was the first Grand Inquisitor, becoming infamous for his zeal and cruelty."], "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For ten points each:", "answers": ["Coxey's Army", "Populist Movement (or Populist Party, or People\u2019s Party)", "silver (or silver dollars)"], "parts": ["Name this 1894 \u201carmy\u201d which marched on Washington D.C. to protest government inaction on unemployment. This march ended after its leaders were protested for trespassing on the U.S. capitol.", "The demands of Coxey\u2019s Army were consistent with this late 19th century ideology, which encouraged democratic control of banks and railroads. James Weaver ran for president with this movement in 1892.", "Many populists wanted to increase coinage of this precious commodity in order to spark inflation and debt reduction. Under the Bland-Allison Act, the federal government ramped up circulation of this metal."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}]}